monstertrak.com 2014-06-25

# Monster Privacy Center | Monster.com

**Your Privacy Rights**

Monster collects information about you and uses this information to help you connect with employers and job seekers and to provide other services to you. This policy describes how your information is collected and used and your choices with respect to your personal information. We encourage you to review our [full Privacy Policy](http://inside.monster.com/fullpolicy/inside2.aspx "full Privacy Policy") for detailed information on our privacy practices.

## Scope of this Policy

This policy applies to information we collect or use on sites and applications owned or controlled by Monster Worldwide, Inc. or its affiliated companies ("Monster").

Monster is not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of ad networks and other websites, third parties with whom we work to provide you personalized services, or those who access your information on our sites or applications.

## Information We Collect

---|---  
  
We collect information about you when you use Monster. We collect information directly from you such as your contact information, resume, and profile information. We also collect information about you automatically such as how you use and interact with Monster, your demographic information, and information about your computer or mobile device.

We may collect or use information about you from publicly-available websites whether or not you have an account with us. You will have the opportunity to claim, change the visibility setting of, or remove the information. However we cannot guarantee that we will not later collect from publicly-available websites other information that pertains to you.

We may also acquire information about you from third parties to further personalize and enhance your experience.

## How We Use Information

We use the information we collect about you to deliver the products and services we offer, respond to you, and operate and improve our sites and applications. Our services include showing you personalized content and advertising on Monster or other sites with which we have a business relationship. We may use your information to contact you about Monster updates, conduct surveys, or to provide informational and service-related communications, including important security updates.

Information you share in public areas of Monster or make visible in the resume and profile database may be accessed, used, and stored by others around the world. We strive to provide a safe environment by attempting to limit access to our database to legitimate users, but we cannot guarantee that unauthorized parties will not gain access. We also cannot control how authorized users store or transfer information you give to us, so you should not post sensitive information to Monster.

## How We Share Information

We do not share contact information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes without your consent.

We share your information with third parties who help us deliver our products and services to you. These third parties may not use your information for any other purpose.

We may share information to third parties if you consent. For example, we may use your information to contact you about products or services available from Monster or our affiliates. If you opt in, we may supply your information to third parties who may contact you about their products or services. You may change your contact preferences by adjusting your [notification settings](http://my.monster.com/Profile/NotificationSettings "notification settings").

We may disclose to third parties information that we have collected from other websites.

We disclose information where legally required.

We may disclose and transfer information to a third party who acquires any or all of Monster's business units.

## How We Store Information

We store your information to make your interaction with Monster more efficient, practical, and relevant. You may access, review, correct, update, or delete your resume or profile any time by [signing in to your account](https://login.monster.com/ "signing in to your account"). If you do not have an account, please [contact us](http://seeker.custhelp.com/app/ask "contact us").

When you delete your personal information, we will retain logs and non-personal information about your activity on Monster. We will also retain an archival copy of your information which is not accessible by you or third parties on the Internet. If your personal information was previously accessed by others using Monster, we are unable to delete the information from their systems.

## Other Information

Monster is not intended for children under 13 years of age.

We participate in the U.S. Department of Commerce's [Safe Harbor Framework](http://inside.monster.com/fullpolicy/inside2.aspx#safe-harbor "Safe Harbor Framework") and we are a member of [TRUSTe](http://inside.monster.com/fullpolicy/inside2.aspx#truste "TRUSTe").

We use cookies to help personalize and maximize your online experience on Monster. You may [turn off cookies](http://inside.monster.com/cookie-info/inside2.aspx "turn off cookies"); however, this will adversely affect your use of Monster.

For information on how to protect yourself online, visit the [Security Center](http://inside.monster.com/security-center/home.aspx "Security Center").

## Contact Information

You may [contact us online](http://my.monster.com/privacy/EmailForm.aspx "contact us online") for questions or concerns about our privacy practices or the Safe Harbor program. You may also write to us at:

Privacy Office  
Monster Worldwide, Inc.  
133 Boston Post Road  
Weston, MA 02493

If you feel we have not properly addressed your question or concern, you may contact [TRUSTe](http://inside.monster.com/fullpolicy/inside2.aspx#contact "TRUSTe") for further assistance.
